今天人们对驾驶的机器人很感兴趣，也称为自驾车
There is a lot of interest today in robots that drive, otherwise known as self driving
汽车和这种技术已经在很长一段时间内被描绘成小说。起源
cars and such technology has been depicted in fiction for a very long time. The origin
自驾车技术可能可以追溯到这两个研究机器人
of self driving car technology can probably be traced back to these two research robots
从20世纪60年代。
from the 1960s.
在左边我们有一台名为斯坦福购物车的机器。这里的这个是由
On the left we have a machine known as the Stanford cart. This one here was built by
汉斯莫拉维克。这个机器人正在做的是使用视觉系统。实际上，立体视觉
Hans Moravec. What this robot is doing is using a vision system. In fact, a stereo vision
系统重建它所驾驶的世界的三维性质。
system to reconstruct the three dimensional nature of the world in which it’s driving.
它使用该信息来规划路径，以避免碰到任何这些障碍。
It uses that information to plan a path so that it can avoid hitting any of these obstacles.
这台机器非常缓慢。主要由有限的计算能力决定
This machine was excruciatingly slow. Mostly dictated by the limited computing power that
早在1964年就可以解决这个问题了。
was available for the problem back in 1964.
右边的机器人也很有名。它被称为Shakey并在SRI开发
The robot on the right is also pretty famous. It’s known as Shakey and developed at SRI
国际在60年代后期，其职业生涯一直持续到70年代。这个机器人也用过
International in the late 60s and its career went on through the 70s. This robot also used
建立一个导航环境地图的愿景。向前迈出了一大步
sense of vision to build a map of the environment in which it was navigating. A major step forward
自驾车技术是2007年DARPA的城市挑战。许多团队参加了比赛
in self driving car technology was the DARPA urban challenge in 2007. A number of teams competed
制造能够与人类驾驶员一样出色的机器人汽车。他们不得不表演
to build robot cars that could perform as well as human drivers. They had to perform
搬进停车位等任务。他们必须在十字路口做正确的事情。
tasks like moving into parking bays. They had to do the right things at the intersections.
他们必须证明他们可以通过技巧安全地超车和所有这些
They had to demonstrate that they could do overtaking and all of this safely with skill
与人类司机相当的水平。
levels comparable to human drivers.
这场比赛的胜利者是卡内基开发的名为“Boss”的机器人车
The winner of that competition was this robot car called, ‘Boss’ developed by Carnegie
梅隆大学，我们可以看到它看起来不像普通的汽车。它的
Mellon University and we can see that it doesn't look anything like an ordinary car. It’s
充满了各种各样的感官装置，大部分车都充满了
bristling with all sorts of sensory devices and a large part of the car is filled with
高性能计算设备。
high performance computing equipment.
现在技术发展得相当快，所以到2014年，谷歌汽车看起来很多
Now technology has evolved pretty rapidly so by the year 2014, Google cars look much
更圆滑。事实上，当你看到它时，只有一个传感器是显而易见的
more sleek. There is really in fact only one sensor that’s obvious when you look at the
汽车，这是在屋顶上称为Velodyne扫描激光测距仪的设备
car and that is the device known as a Velodyne scanning laser range finder on the roof of
车。机器人汽车看待它的世界的方式在这里被称为点云
the car. The way the robot car sees its world is shown here in what we call a point cloud
这是由我们在Google汽车上看到的Velodyne扫描仪生成的。
image and this is generated by that Velodyne scanner that we saw on top of the Google car.
点云是三维空间中的多个点，并且它们通常是颜色
The point cloud is a number of points in three dimensional space and they are typically color
编码。因此颜色为蓝色，冷色调表示机器人所在的地平面
coded. So the colors blue, the cool colors indicate the ground plane on which the robot
正在行驶并且指向地面以上的地方可能不明智地驾驶着色
is driving and points above the ground plane where it might be imprudent to drive are colored
绿色或红色表示高于地平面的那些点。所以从此
green or red for those points that are very high above the ground plane. So from this
相当简单的三维几何模型的世界周围的汽车，
fairly simple three dimensional geometric model of the world surrounding the car, the
车上的软件能够做出一些关于哪个方向的决定
software on board the car is able to make a number of decisions about which direction
它应该开车。
it should drive.
它可以看到其他物体，也许是人类，也许是其他汽车，也许是道路标志。
It’s able to see other objects perhaps human beings, perhaps other cars, perhaps road signs.
车辆上的软件必须采取所有这些丰富的感官信息并创建
The software on board the vehicle has to take all of this rich sensory information and create
一个计划，然后发送命令到汽车调整方向盘或调整
a plan and then send commands to the car to adjust the steering wheel or to adjust the
油门或调整制动器。
throttle or to adjust the brake.